<resources>
<string name="help_text" translation_description="Please do not change the &lt; and &gt; markup">
&lt;big&gt;&lt;b&gt;TransientGO for Android&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Version %s&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;https://github.com/sky-map-team/stardroid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Introduction and Quick Start&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
TransientGO turns your Android-powered mobile phone into a window on the
night sky.  When you point your phone up you will see a map of the brightest
stars, constellations, and planets in that part of the sky.&lt;br/&gt;Next time you see a
bright  star and want to know what it\'s called, use TransientGO!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Navigation Modes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When first installed TransientGO is in Automatic Mode and uses the phone\'s sensors
to show you a map of the sky in the direction you are holding the phone.  By
switching into Manual Mode, you can drag the map with your finger to explore the
sky.  Move the trackball or D-pad left and right to rotate the map.  On multitouch phones
you can also rotate the map with two fingers and use a pinch gesture to zoom in and out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Night Vision Mode&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Night Vision Mode is designed to protect your dark-adapted eyes.  When you
select the Night Vision menu option, TransientGO will display the map in a red
color, dim the screen and switch off the button backlights.
Select the option again to revert to normal colors.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Setting Your Location&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
TransientGO needs your approximate location in order to show you the correct star
map.  By default, it will determine this from your cellular network.  If you are
out of range, or have network location disabled it will use your phone\'s GPS.
You can also set your location manually via the settings menu, either by
supplying a place name or as a latitude and longitude (in degrees.)  Note that
TransientGO requires a data connection to determine your latitude and longitude from
a place name.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Troubleshooting and Limitations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The map is inaccurate.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If you find that the map does not accurately line up with the real sky there
could be a number of reasons:&lt;br/&gt;
1) Is your compass calibrated?  Try holding the phone and rotating your wrist in
figures of eight to calibrate it.  You may need to repeat this at intervals
- this is a feature of the phone, rather than TransientGO.&lt;br/&gt;
2) Does the application have an accurate fix on your location?  Is your GPS or
network location turned on?&lt;br/&gt;
3) Do you have the correct time and timezone set?
TransientGO needs to calculate Universal Time, and it needs your local time AND
timezone to do this.  If your device has a SIM card then these will usually be
set correctly.&lt;br/&gt;
4) Do you have magnetic correction switched on?  In some parts of the world the
difference between magnetic North and True North can be as much as 20 degrees.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The map does not move&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Are you in manual mode?  If not, this could be due to an uncalibrated compass.
Follow the steps above to \'unstick\' it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Credits&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Developers (SUNY Oswego)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Landon Patmore, Zackary Keller, Dominic Dewhurst, Jacob Brooks, Sushmita Banerjee&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;i&gt;Advisers (SUNY Oswego)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Dr. James Early, Dr. Shashi Kanbur&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;i&gt;Advisers (Caltech)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ashish Mahabal, Andrew Drake&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Data&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Transient Data Stream(https://4pisky.org)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
TransientGO is based off of "Google Sky Map":
Sky Map was originally developed as "Google Sky Map" by Google Inc. and open sourced
in 2012.
Sky Map uses maps derived from data from:&lt;br/&gt;
Centre de Donnees astronomiques de Strasbourg (http://cdsweb.u-strasbg.fr/)&lt;br/&gt;
The Bright Star Catalogue, 5th Revised Ed. (Hoffleit D., Warren Jr W.H.)&lt;br/&gt;
The HYG Database, HYG v1.0. (http://www.astronexus.com/)&lt;br/&gt;
History and Accurate Positions for the NGC/IC Objects (Harold G. Corwin Jr)&lt;br/&gt;
Revised New General Catalogue of Nonstellar Astronomical Objects
(Sulentic J.W., Tifft W.G.)&lt;br/&gt;
SFA Star Charts
(http://observe.phy.sfasu.edu/SFAStarCharts/SFAStarChartFAQ.html)&lt;br/&gt;
Positions of Solar System Objects are calculated from data provided by the USNO
(http://www.usno.navy.mil/USNO/astronomical-applications)&lt;br/&gt;
Spherical coverage data obtained from
(http://www2.research.att.com/~njas/coverings)&lt;br/&gt;
</string>
</resources>
